Guide to the J.D. Graham Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal and Family Papers, 1804-89; Series VII; 4; (10 boxes)
  - WILLIAM MONTROSE GRAHAM (Son)
    - "Fort Riley, Kansas, Light Batteries, Genrl. Wm. Montrose Graham's command", 1870 (Box 40, Folder 703)
    - Presidio officers, Genl. Graham's command, 1888 Jul 8 (Box 40, Folder 704)
    - Presidio officers, Genl. Graham's command, 1889 Apr (Box 40, Folder 705)
    - "Views of Santa Cruz, Cal., and vicinity," by Geo. Webb [artillery unit posed], 1889 Sep 3 (Box 40, Folder 706)
    - Presidio, Light Battery K, Graham's command, 1889 (Box 40, Folder 707)
    - Presidio officers, Graham's command, ca. 1889 (Box 40, Folder 708)
    - "Our Chapel. Presidio, San Francisco, California", n.d. (Box 40, Folder 709)
    - [Presidio, Light Battery K ?], n.d. (Box 40, Folder 710)
    - Military unit moving on a beach, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 711)
    - Artillery, [19th century] (Box 40, Folder 712)
    - Four officers posing with a mounted gun, [19th century] (Box 40, Folder 713)
- Cornelius E. Clifford Papers, 1893-96; Series VIII; 0.25; (1 box)
  Cornelius E. Clifford Papers consists of correspondence and a handwritten speech.
  - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 41, Folder 714-17)
  - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 41, Folder 718-19)
  - Speech on Robert Emmet, Irish rebel, ca. 1893 (Box 41, Folder 720)
- Oversize, 9.5; (9 boxes)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series II-VIII. The arrangement, which is based on size, parallels that of the collection.
  - SERIES II. GENERAL MILITARY PAPERS
    - Other Papers
      - A Report upon the Military and Hydrographical Chart of the Extremity of Cape Cod including the townships of Provincetown and Truro with their seacoasts and ship harbor, 1838 (Box 42, Folder 721)
      - Army and Navy Official Gazette, 1862-63 (Box 42, Folder 722)
  - SERIES III. NORTH EASTERN BOUNDARY SURVEY
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - "Determination of the time, by observed equal altitudes of the Sun's limbs", 1840-55 (Box 42, Folder 723)
  - SERIES VI. GREAT LAKES IMPROVEMENTS & LAKES SURVEY
    - Reports, Plans, Maps
      - Reports of Graham's Work
        - "Instructions for determining differences of Longitude by the aid of signals produced by flashing small charges of gun powder at night", 1863 Jun 11 (Box 42, Folder 724)
        - "Report of Assistant J. M. Bigelow to Col. Graham...upon the...relation of winds and clouds to barometric pressure at Sacketts Harbor, Thunder Bay, and Superior City", 1863 Oct 1 (Box 42, Folder 725)
        - "Survey of the Northern and Northwestern Lakes. Annual Report of ...Graham...for the year 1863", 1863 Oct (Box 42, Folder 726)
        - "The lunar tide in lake Michigan" [corrections to report published in annual report to Topographical Engineers, Oct 31 1860, including tables], [1863] (Box 42, Folder 727)
        - "Description of the large diagrams exhibiting the actual state of the barometer, winds, rains and clouds at Superior City, Thunder Bay and Sacketts Harbor", [1863] (Box 42, Folder 728)
        - Comparison of water level of several lakes from 1859 to 1863 (Box 42, Folder 729)
        - "Monthly Meteorological registers at the fourteen (14) stations", [1863] (Box 42, Folder 730)
      - Other Reports and Papers
        - "Bond of the Illinois Central Rail Road Company and Conditions in reference to the opening in the U.S. South pier at Chicago for said company's benefit", 1855 (Box 42, Folder 731)
  - SERIES VII. PERSONAL AND FAMILY PAPERS
    - James Duncan Graham
      - Deeds, leases, mortgages and other property documents, 1836-64, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 732)
      - Insurance documents, 1855-68 (Box 42, Folder 733)
  - SERIES II. GENERAL MILITARY PAPERS
    - Maps
      - Sketch of the Public Surveys in Iowa Territory, [1827-28] (Box 43, Folder 734)
      - Sketch of the Public Surveys in Wisconsin Territory, [1827-28] (Box 43, Folder 735)
      - A diagram of the triangulation for the survey of the coast of the United States ...Connecticut and Long Island, 1834 (Box 43, Folder 736)
      - Map exhibiting the position of the several lines connected with the settlement of the Ohio boundary question (accompanied by 3 related maps), 1835 (Box 43, Folder 737)
      - Survey of a ship canal around the falls of Niagara, ca. 1835-36 (Box 43, Folder 738)
      - Map of the seat of war in east Florida, 1837 (Box 43, Folder 739)
      - Map of the Cherokee cession in Alabama, 1837-38 (Box 43, Folder 740)
      - Arkansas. Map of Arkansas surveying district shewing the extent of the public surveys (two versions), 1837, 1839 (Box 43, Folder 741)
      - A plat exhibiting the surveys as they are in the Territory of Florida (two versions), 1837, 1839 (Box 43, Folder 742)
      - Map of...various routes surveyed for the Western & Atlantic Rail Road of Georgia, 1837 (Box 43, Folder 743)
      - Diagram of the state of Illinois (two versions), 1837, 1839 (Box 43, Folder 744)
      - Map of the south western district Louisiana (three copies, two versions), [1837-40] (Box 43, Folder 745)
      - St. Helena district La. (two versions), [1837-40] (Box 43, Folder 746)
      - Southeastern district Louisiana (two versions), [1837-40] (Box 43, Folder 747)
      - Map of the District North of Red River La. (two versions), [1837-40] (Box 43, Folder 748)
      - Diagram of the state of Missouri (two versions), 1837, 1839 (Box 43, Folder 749)
      - Core Sound North Carolina (accompanied by four related maps), 1837 (Box 43, Folder 750)
      - Sketch of the public lands in the north part of Michigan, [1839-40] (Box 43, Folder 751)
      - Diagram of the surveying district South Tennessee, [1839-40] (Box 43, Folder 752)
      - Map of Texas and the countries adjacent: compiled... for the State Department (two copies each with annotations by Graham), 1844 (Box 43, Folder 753)
      - Map of Texas and part of New Mexico compiled in the Bureau...chiefly for military purposes (four copies each with annotations by Graham), 1857 (Box 43, Folder 754)
      - Kansas with parts of the neighboring states and territories, 1868 Oct (Box 43, Folder 755)
      - [Map of the Mississippi River from Chuteau's Island to St. Louis] (Box 43, Folder 756)
      - "Chart of the Tamasi River, surveyed and drawn by Capt. W. Cole for Col. Gates" (Box 43, Folder 757)
  - SERIES III. NORTH EASTERN BOUNDARY SURVEY
    - Reports, Plans, Letters, Maps
      - Map showing Portage Lake, Maine, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 758)
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - Lists of latitude and longitude of various places, 1841-45, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 759)
    - Administrative Records
      - Muster rolls, 1844-52 (Box 44, Folder 760-68)
      - Clothing accounts, 1848, 1850 (Box 44, Folder 769-70)
  - SERIES IV. MASON-DIXON LINE SURVEY
    - Reports and Maps
      - Maps of the Mason-Dixon line near Delaware Bay and head of the Chesapeake Bay and triangulation figure (three sketches) (Box 44, Folder 771)
  - SERIES V. MEXICAN BOUNDARY SURVEY
    - Reports, Plans, Letters, Maps
      - Barometric profile of the route from San Antonio ... to the Copper Mines of Santa Rita in New Mexico, in 1851... by...Graham, accompanied by his notes (Box 44, Folder 772)
      - Three maps referred to in Graham's report to the Secretary of the Interior, Senate Ex. Doc. 121, 32nd Congress, 1st session, 1851 (Box 44, Folder 773)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1852, 1855 (Box 44, Folder 774)
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - "Determination of the line and latitude of Indianola, Texas", 1851 Apr 25 (Box 44, Folder 775)
  - SERIES VI. GREAT LAKES IMPROVEMENTS & LAKES SURVEY
    - Reports, Plans, Maps
      - Reports of Graham's Work
        - Chart of Chicago Harbor Illinois shewing the main entrance for ships, and the state of the bar after completing the dredging..., 1854 (Box 45, Folder 776)
        - Map of the seafloor off Racine Light House by J. R. Mayer, 1863 Jun 27 (Box 45, Folder 777)
        - "Sketch showing the progress made in the survey of Green Bay, its entrances and the adjacent coast of Lake Michigan", 1863 (Box 45, Folder 778)
        - Map of Green Bay, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 779)
        - Map of Washington Island and Surrounding Bays (Box 45, Folder 780)
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - Lunar Tides
        - "A Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan. Table A Continued", 1857-58 (Box 45, Folder 781)
        - "Office Copy. Table A5 of the Annual Report of 1862 (Same as A12 of the Report of 1860 corrected)", [1858-63] (Box 45, Folder 782)
        - "For the Topl. Bureau. Table A5 of the Annual Report of 1862 (Same as A12 of the Report of 1860 corrected) and the same as H5 of the Report of 1863", [1858-63] (Box 45, Folder 783)
        - "Investigation of the problem of a Lunar Tide on Lake Michigan" and [Tables of times of moon's meridian transit], 1858-59 (Box 45, Folder 784)
  - SERIES VI. GREAT LAKES IMPROVEMENTS & LAKES SURVEY
    - Reports, Plans, Maps
      - Reports of Graham's Work
        - Sketch of unknown harbor, with soundings, 1855 Sep 30 (Box 46, Folder 785)
      - Other Reports and Papers
        - Iron Pile light house to be erected on Coffins Patches, Florida Coast, U.S., 1856 (Box 46, Folder 786)
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - Determining Longitude
        - Final computations for time at Chicago, Fulton, Albany, and Lyons, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 787)
        - Original computations of the latitudes of Fulton, Ills., Albany, Ill., and Lyons, Iowa, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 788)
        - Miscellaneous, 1858, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 789)
      - Lunar Tide
        - "Table A13. Investigation of the Problem of a lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Showing the quarter-hourly coordinates of altitude of the surface of Lake Michigan observed during the twenty-six spring tides...", 1859 (Box 46, Folder 790)
        - "A Lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Table D. Quarter hourly observations made at and near the several periods of the conjunction and opposition of the sun and moon between January 3d and June 2d shewing the character of the spring tidal wave on Lake Michigan", 1859 (Box 46, Folder 791)
        - "Tabulation of Spring Tides (not used in this form)", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 792)
      - Statistics on Harbors - Exports and Imports
        - Chicago Harbor, 1854-56 (Box 46, Folder 793)
  - SERIES VII. PERSONAL AND FAMILY PAPERS
    - JAMES DUNCAN GRAHAM
      - National Intelligencer (Washington newspaper, two issues, July 23, 28), 1864 (Box 46, Folder 794)
  - SERIES VI. GREAT LAKES IMPROVEMENTS & LAKES SURVEY
    - Data from Observations and Calculations
      - Lunar Tide
        - "A lunar tide on Lake Michigan. Table B", 1858-59 (Box 47, Folder 795)
        - Diagrams of lunar tide on Lake Michigan, [1858-63] (Box 47, Folder 796)
        - "Rough copy, in pencil of the Lake Michigan tide register", [1859] (Box 47, Folder 797)
    - Administrative Records
      - Property Returns - Harbors
        - Black Lake Harbor, Michigan, 1855 (Box 47, Folder 798)
        - Chicago Harbor, Illinois, 1854-63 (Box 47, Folder 799-801)
        - Cleveland Harbor, Ohio, 1857, 1861 (Box 47, Folder 802)
        - Dunkirk Harbor, New York, 1857-60 (Box 47, Folder 803-04)
        - Erie Harbor, Pennsylvania, 1857-61 (Box 48, Folder 805-06)
        - Kenosha Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855 (Box 48, Folder 807)
        - Manitowoc Harbor, Wisconsin, 1854-60 (Box 48, Folder 808)
        - Michigan City Harbor, Indiana, 1855-56 (Box 48, Folder 809-10)
        - Milwaukee Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855-57 (Box 48, Folder 811-13)
        - New Buffalo Harbor, Michigan, 1855-56, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 814-15)
        - Oswego Harbor, New York, 1857-62 (Box 49, Folder 816-17)
        - St. Joseph, Michigan, 1856-60 (Box 49, Folder 818)
        - Sheboygan Harbor, Wisconsin, 1855-56 (Box 49, Folder 819)
          - Waukegan Harbor, Illinois, 1855-57 (Box 49, Folder 820-21)
      - Other Property Returns
        - Chicago light house, 1857, 1859 (Box 50, Folder 822)
        - Steam dredge, 1855-61, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 823-26)
  - SERIES VII. PERSONAL AND FAMILY PAPERS
    - Lawrence Pike Graham (Half-Brother)
      - "Sketch of the march of Bvt. Maj. L. P. Graham, 2d Drag. from Monterey, Mexico to San Diego, California" accompanied by a list of places and distances, 1849 (Box 50, Folder 827)